opinion-people.com 2018-12-27

# We take your privacy seriously! | opinion-people

### Personal data remain confidential at all times

We treat your personal data and information as strictly confidential. Market research studies are always analyzed anonymously. When a client collects their market research data from our surveys, they only receive the consolidated results of a study and never your personal data.

### Everything meets strict legal requirements

The data are collected, processed and used in line with the strict requirements of the UK data protection law [<https://www.gov.uk/data-protection]>. Opinion people only processes and uses the data collected as far as is necessary to carry out market research, legally admissible and specified by you. The data for the individual studies are analyzed in anonymized form. We would like to stress that your address data (which we require for winning notifications) is kept completely separate from your answers. Your consent is voluntary and may be withdrawn at any time. We also comply with the general data privacy provisions and legal guidelines of ESOMAR (European Society for Opinion and Marketing Research). If you would like more information, please do not hesitate to contact us by e-mail on [panelteam-uk@opinion-people.com](mailto:panelteam-uk@opinion-people.com) or via the contact form. 

### Market research is not marketing

The data collected by Norstat via Opinion People is used to map habits, attitudes and preferences for commercial and research-related purposes. You will never be asked to purchase products or services, nor will you receive third party advertisements. The personal information collected through Opinion People will not be disclosed to third parties unless you explicitly consent to this.

### What types of personal data about you we collect, and why

Depending on what information you have given us, we store a number of personal data about you like name, age, gender, zip-code, your phone number and street address. 

We use information about age, gender and zip-code, along with your answers to the profile questions, to decide what surveys to invite you to. Based on this information we determine whether or not you are in the target demographic of a survey, so we can reduce the risk of inviting you to a survey that you will not be able to complete. 

We process your contact information to be able to invite you to surveys, and to give you incentives when you have completed surveys. We also store information about what surveys you have been invited to, and which ones you have completed, to be able to correctly assign panel points. We do however not store any information in your profile about your responses to survey questions.

All information we have stored about you is available under My Page in the panel pages. 

### Your membership and our use of your data

As a member of Opinion People, you grant Norstat the right to pass on data you have provided in your profile and data you provide in a survey to customers in a statistically processed form and in a form that is anonymized. Name, postal address, email address or other personal information that could identify individuals will not be passed on to our customers or others without prior explicit consent to this. As a member of Opinion People you answer the surveys you want when it suits you.

Information you provided in specific audience inquiry questions cannot be edited via your user account. However, you can view and delete this information at any time by signing in to your user account.

We reserve the right, without notice, to report members suspected of answering surveys with low quality, including when checking response time or response patterns. The member will also lose his accumulated points if it appears that the answers are of such poor quality that they cannot be used in our analysis work. It is not allowed to register more than one user account or email address in the panel per person. Duplicate accounts, with corresponding points, will be deleted without notice. 

### Data storage

Your profile is saved as long as you are a member of Opinion People. If you choose to opt out of the panel, we will delete all information about you. When processing anonymous data sets, our systems may require data files containing personal information, such as email that enables us to send you an invitation to participate in a survey. We will retain your survey data for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy, when the purpose is fulfilled we will automatically delete data files containing information that can identify you.

### Rewards

When you redeem you points you can buy products, digital coupons and make donations. If you choose to exchange points for digital coupons, we might transfer a system generated Redemption ID to our 3rd party system vendor. The vendor will keep a log with your Redemption ID, date and product. We only share information necessary to complete the transaction and never personal identifiable data.

### Our use of cookies

A cookie is a small text file which stores information on your computer. It is used on many websites to give you as visitor access to various features like logging in and remembering what you did the last time you visited the site.

### Our member site cookies and survey cookies

We are using cookies to handle login on our site and in some of our surveys to provide a better service.

### 3rd Party Cookies

Norstat can place cookies on behalf of our clients, but only if you have given explicit consent to this. These cookies enable processing of your personal data and information you have provided while answering our surveys and is delivered to our client along with the cookie we have placed on their behalf. The client will combine this information with other information they have on your digital behaviour. The purpose is to identify target groups similar to you they can direct marketing effort towards. These marketing efforts will NOT be targeted at you. This consent can be withdrawn at any time by logging in to your user account. 

You have the opportunity to look at and edit which 3rd parties you have given us permission to share information with via your user account. Through your user account, you also have the opportunity to withdraw your consent at any time. To delete history, you will also need to delete cookies from your browser.

### Google Analytics 

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google, Inc. (“Google”). Google Analytics uses “cookies”, which are text files placed on your computer, to help the website analyze how users use the site. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website will be transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States.

In case IP-anonymization is activated on this website, your IP address will be truncated within the area of Member States of the European Union or other parties to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases the whole IP address will be first transferred to a Google server in the USA and truncated there. The IP-anonymization is active on this website.

Google will use this information on behalf of the operator of this website for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports on website activity for website operators and providing them other services relating to website activity and internet usage.

The IP-address, that your Browser conveys within the scope of Google Analytics, will not be associated with any other data held by Google. You may refuse the use of cookies by selecting the appropriate settings on your browser, however please note that if you do this you may not be able to use the full functionality of this website. You can also opt-out from being tracked by Google Analytics with effect for the future by downloading and installing Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on for your current web browser: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>. 

### Google Tag Manager

Google Tag Manager is a service provided by Google. The Google Tag Manager is a platform / code management tool. The tool does not collect any personal data, but causes the triggering of other tags, which may contain your data. Google Tag Manager does not access this data. If disabling is done at the domain or cookie level, it will persist for all tracking tags that are implemented with Google Tag Manager.

### Voucher offers of Sovendus GmbH 

In order to select a currently interesting voucher offer for you, we will transmit your pseudonymised hash value of your e-mail address and your IP-address in encrypted form to Sovendus GmbH, Moltkestrasse 11, D-76133 Karlsruhe (Sovendus) (Art. 6 par. 1 f GDPR). The pseudonymised hash value of your e-mail address is used to consider a possibly existing objection to receive offers from Sovendus (Art. 21 par.3, Art. 6 par. 1 c GDPR). The IP-address will be exclusively used for data security purposes and as a rule the same will be anonymised after seven days (Art. 6 Abs.1 f DSGVO). Furthermore, we will transmit order number, order value with currency, session ID, coupon code, and time stamp in pseudonymised form to Sovendus for billing purposes (Art. 6 Abs.1 f DSGVO). If you are interested in a voucher offer of Sovendus, while there is no objection existing to receive such offers, and if you click on the voucher banner, we will transmit your form of address, your name and your e-mail address in encrypted form to Sovendus to prepare a voucher (Art. 6 par. 1 b, f GDPR). You will find further information about the processing of your data by Sovendus in their Online Data Protection Notice at [www.sovendus.co.uk/privacy_policy](http://www.sovendus.co.uk/privacy_policy). 

### User ID

An individual user ID is assigned to incoming members as soon as you enter your contact data and accept these general terms and conditions. Under this UserID, all registration entries and transactions are stored. By using and storing such a UserID, we are able to allocate registrations to our partners, campaigns and advertisements, and thus measure the long-term performance of the same, which helps us to continually improve our performance potential. You agree to the storage and use of the UserID.

### NORSTAT and GDPR

The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is a regulation by which the European Commission intends to strengthen and unify data protection for individuals within the European Union (EU). It applies from 25 May 2018. 

GDPR legislates a lot of common sense data security ideas, especially from the Privacy by Design school of thought: 

\\\ Minimize collection of personally identifiable information.  
\\\ Delete personally identifiable information that is no longer necessary   
\\\ Restrict access and secure data through its entire lifecycle

Norstat have been preparing systems and routines to implement the GDPR for a long time. Norstat systems and routines ensures data will be safe, both in terms of GDPR requirements and business protection.

### Your rights as a data subject

You have the right to view all personal data we have stored about you. Norstat will provide all the information necessary to ensure legal, fair and transparent processing of personal information. We will always inform you about the purpose of processing, what categories of data we are processing, with whom (if any) we have shared your information, information about the retention period for data and your rights as concerns the processing. However, your right to view data is limited when it comes to historical responses to single surveys. This is because the responses are stored in pseudomized form and not connected to your userID, and therefore to track down historical responses require a considerable about of manual processing. If it is still important to you to view such historical data, you will have to specify what data you are requiring insight in.

You also have the right to withdraw your consent to our processing and storing your personal data, by ending your membership. Should you wish to do so, you may cancel your membership directly from the "my details" section of the panel pages, or by contacting our support department.

### About us and this privacy policy

This privacy statement addresses how Norstat collects and processes data about you. If you have further questions about processing and processing your data, please contact us through our Data Protection Officer, Tone Belsvik.
